Chia-Hsiang Kao

Updated January 21, 2022

★ Homepage

☑ Primary

☑ School

ChiaHsiang0326

□ (+886) 972-152-536

Research Interests

My goal is to develop robust and interpretable machine learning algorithms and systems that operate reliably even under challenging conditions. Along with my research goals, I am interested in model robustness, unbiased and generalized representation learning, explainable AI, and healthcare applications.

Education

National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University (NYCU)

Taipei, Taiwan

Doctor of Medicine

Aug. 2015 - Jun. 2022

- Overall GPA: 3.81/4.0, Major GPA: 3.82/4.0, CS-related GPA: 3.90/4.0

PS: National Yang Ming University (NYMU) and National Chiao Tung University merged in 2021. I originally studied in NYMU. PS: In Taiwan, high school students can be directly admitted to medical schools without Bachelor's degree.

Publications

• MAML is a Noisy Contrastive Learner | Paper | Slides |

Chia-Hsiang Kao, Wei-Chen Chiu, and Pin-Yu Chen

[ICLR'22] [NeurIPS'21 workshop, oral presentation]

- Proved that MAML belongs to supervised contrastive learning.
- Proposed a zeroing trick that significantly improves the convergence of MAML.
- Demystifying T1-MRI to FDG¹⁸-PET Image Translation via Representational Similarity | Paper | Chia-Hsiang Kao, Yong-Sheng Chen, Li-Fen Chen, and Wei-Chen Chiu

[MICCAI'21, oral presentation]

- Hypothesized and verified that medical image translation models implicitly segment brain tissue types and identify brain regions.
- o Unravelling the Spatio-Temporal Neurodynamics of Rhythm Encoding-Reproduction Networks by a Novel fMRI Autoencoder | Paper |

Chia-Hsiang Kao, Ching-Ju Yang, Li-Kai Cheng, Hsin-Yen Yu, Yong-Sheng Chen, Jen-Chuen Hsieh, and Li-Fen Chen [NER'19 (International IEEE/EMBS Conference on Neural Engineering)]

- Proposed a novel autoencoder to untangle the spatio-temporal patterns of neurodynamics.
- Identified the rhythm encoding-reproduction networks of the brain.

Research Experiences

Laboratory of Precision Psychiatry, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Student

Sep. 2021 - Jun. 2022

- Advisor: Professor Albert Chih-Chieh Yang.
- Estimated patients' cognitive function based on their drawings.

Enriched Vision Applications Lab, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University Research Student

Hsinchu, Taiwan Sep. 2020 - Sep. 2021

o Advisor: Professor Wei-Chen Chiu and MIT-IBM Watson AI Lab Researcher Pin-Yu Chen.

- Proved that MAML is a supervised contrastive learning algorithm.
- Studied theories of self-supervised learning and adversarial learning.

Brain Mapping Laboratory, National Yang Ming Chiao Tung University

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Student

Sep. 2017 - Sep. 2020

- Advisor: Professor <u>Li-Fen Chen</u>.
- Utilized explainable AI tools to understand the inner behavior of image translation models.
- Analyzed fMRI, MRI, and CT data and built various predictive models.

Institute of Information Science, Academia Sinica

Taipei, Taiwan

Research Intern

Jun. 2017 - Sep. 2017

- Advisor: Professor Meng-Chang Chen.
- Analyzed air quality data and built air pollution predictive models.

Clinical Experiences

Taipei Veteran General Hospital

Taipei, Taiwan

Medical Intern

Jan. 2022 - Jun. 2022

Served as a second-year intern doctor in Internal Medicine, Surgery, ICU, Emergency Medicine, OB/GYN, etc. I
was responsible for the primary care of the inpatient in those departments.

Chi Mei Medical Center Tainai, Taiwan

Medical Intern Nov. 2021 - Dec. 2021

• Served as an intern doctor in Internal Medicine and Emergency Medicine.

Taipei Veteran General Hospital

Taipei, Taiwan

Medical Intern

Oct. 2019 - Sep. 2020

• Served as a first-year intern doctor in Internal Medicine, Surgery, Radiology, Pediatrics, OB/GYN, Family Medicine, etc. I was responsible for the primary care of the inpatient in those departments.

Scholarships, Honors, and Services

 Junior Reviewer, NeurIPS'21 Workshop 	Oct. 2021
• Student Travel Award, MICCAI'21: To first author student with the highest scoring.	Jun. 2021
 College Student Research Scholarships, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan 	Jul. 2020
 College Student Research Scholarships, Ministry of Science and Technology, Taiwan 	Jul. 2018
• Summer Research Scholarships, National Health Research Institutes, Taiwan	Jul. 2018

Courses

Computer Science *	Introduction to Computer Science	A+
	Java Programming Language G	B+
	Theory of Computability G	A+
	Machine Learning G	A+
	Reinforcement Learning G	A+
Computer Science **	Data Structures and Algorithms	
-	Operative Systems	
Mathematics *	Calculus (Honor)	B+
	Probability	A-
	Introduction to Analysis (Honor)	A-
	Advanced Probability G	A
Mathematics **	Linear Algebra	
	Statistics	
	Differential Equation	

Skills and Others

Languages Mandarin (Native)

English (Fluent, TOEFL: 106/120)

Programming Python (PyTorch, TensorFlow, Keras, OpenCV, Scikit-learn)

MATLAB

JAVA

Interests Jogging and Writing [▶ Medium]